

TARANJIT KANG

(416)-262-5019
Taranjitk18@gmail.com
www.GitHub.com/Tarnn
7470 Macphersons Lane,
Puslinch, ON

OBJECTIVE



To continue to grow and learn as a developer, in order to become a better developer.

Understands the core fundamentals and concepts of Java.

Good understanding of Spring boot and Spring MVC for creating RESTful API and Microservices.

.....

Familiar in building and deploying web applications consuming RESTful services.

Experienced in Database integration with SQL and NoSQL for data persistence and retrieval.

Strong experience with Front-end technologies such as Angular JS (Angular 2,4,5,6).

Effective unit testing with Jasmine and test runner Karma.

Excellent with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript/Typescript.

Experienced with version control systems such as Git, and providing excellent documentation.

Worked with various templating engines such as; Jade(PUG), Handlebars, EJS, SASS.

Experience working with package managers; Gradle, Maven, NPM, Yarn, Bower.

Experience with front-end web frameworks such as; Bootstrap 3/4, Foundation.

Proficient with WAI-ARIA for creating accessible user interfaces for exception user experiences.

Strong understanding of various build tools such as Jenkins, Gulp, Grunt to automate build process.

Experience with cloud platforms for deployment such as IBM Cloud Foundary/Bluemix.

Adept with the understanding of software development methodologies such as; Agile and Waterfall.



JOB EXPERIENCES

NCR (National Cash Register) - Waterloo

Enhanced and created new functionality for customer/teller-based application, consumed by US Bank. Learned proprietary *Yaml* based SDK Api-toolkit, which featured yaml list code configured to *Java* actions for performing essential tasks and communicating with containerized *Java Spring Boot* microservices. Deployed containerized packaged application via *Docker* and *Kubernetes* to local cluster environment via docker and kubectl. Created E2E tests for development features with *Cucumber*. Used *BitBucket* as SCM, *Microsoft Teams*, *Confluence* and *Jira* for team collaboration. Configured DEV environment setup via *Vagrant*. Acted as release master and build master, which entails ownership over release to prod process, as well as monitored *Jenkins* pipelines to ensure green CI/CD. Followed agile principles and methodologies, with 2-week sprints.

Environment: Yaml + SPeL, Java, Spring Boot (Microservices), Cucumber, Docker, Kubernetes, Vagrant, Jenkins, Bitbucket, GitLab Microsoft Teams, Slack

Intuit (QuickBooks Online Accountant) - Mississauga

Acted as the sole backend developer for Workpapers Canada for QuickBooks Online Accountant. Developed new and updated existing <code>Graphql/RESTful</code> api for Workpapers feature which essentially allows the accountant to organize a client's books efficiently, in order to prep for taxes. Developed via <code>Java Spring Boot</code> (<code>Microservice</code>) for integration with a <code>React</code> front end. <code>Flyway dB</code> for schema management, <code>Orika Mapper</code> for dto mapping. <code>Docker</code> for containerizing application. Used <code>Splunk</code> for log tracing and debugging. Created test cases via <code>JUnit</code> and ensured <code>Jacoco</code> code coverage was well above required limit. Followed <code>agile</code> methodologies and participated in daily scrum and task estimation. Used <code>Jira</code>, <code>Confluence</code> and <code>Slack</code> for team collaboration. Used <code>GitHub</code> for scm and participated in PR review process.

.....

Environment: Java, Spring Boot (Microservices), GraphQL, Apollo, REST, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS (SQS, STS, SNS), Jacoco, J-Unit, FlywayDB, Darkly, Argo CD, Splunk, Jenkins, Git, Slack, Agile, SQL

Express Scripts (NIHB) - Mississauga

Enhanced and created new features, for a complete re-designed e-health system. Primarily used *Java*, *Spring Boot*, *GraphQL* in the creation of *Microservices*. Created test cases to keep a consistent good rating for code coverage on sonar. Developed *RESTful* apis to communicate with *SQL* database and *Angular5/6/7* Front end. Created and enhanced components for features, using Reactive Programming Patterns and GraphQL (Apollo Client). Developed and fixed test cases using *Jasmine*. Participated in agile methodology, and sprints

Environment: Java, Spring Boot (Microservices), Typescript, Angular 5/6/7, RxJS, GraphQL, Apollo, Material UI, Jasmine, Karma, CSS3, Agile, SQL

Software Engineer
Dec 2019 – Present
Contract

Java Developer

Apr 2019 – Dec 2019 Contract

Full Stack Developer
Lead
Jan 2019 – Apr 2019
Contract

Rogers (Today's Shopping Choice) - Mississauga

Client Server

Developer

June 2018 – Dec 2018

Contract

Enhanced eCommerce client application (TSC), using primarily JavaScript/Typescript, JQuery, Angular 4/5, and webpack. Programmed backend with ASP C# code and elastic search to communicate with front end, as well as MySQL for developing new data pipelines. Worked with Oracle Endeca (CMS) for displaying different cartridges and data on frontend. Developed elastic search queries to retrieve data from Vue. Followed agile principles and participated in scrum and task estimation. Developed QA Automation regression test cases with Python and Selenium and Selenium Grid.

Environment: Javascript, Typescript, Angular 2/4/5, C#, Elasticsearch, Python, Selenium, Oracle Endeca, Agile, Microsoft Teams

Royal Bank of Canada (PSH & BFS) - Toronto

TECHNICAL SYSTEMS ANALYST

May 2017 – May 2018 Full-time Upgraded existing UI for business banking clients: Rbc Express, using Angular 4 & Bootstrap. Conducted unit tests using Jasmine and Karma test runner as well as mock services to prototype scenarios. Also developed RESTful microservices with Spring MVC and IBM RAD in order to integrate with Angular front-end to create seamless transitions of various business flows. Used Jenkins and IBM Cloud Foundry for continuous integration for building and deploying build artefacts. Used GitHub for version control and team collaboration. Additionally, worked within an AGILE environment for continuous feedback and integration and participated in weekly scrum meetings.

Environment: Typescript, Javascript, Angular, Karma, Jasmine, Java, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Jenkins, REST, IBM CF, Jacoco, Git, Agile



EDUCATION

SHERIDAN COLLEGE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (SC)

ONTARIO COLLEGE ADVANCED DIPLOMA

Attended for Software Development & Network Engineering (co-op).
Previously enrolled with a 4.0 GPA.

Member of the Sheridan Coding Syndicate Club.

Sept 2015 - May 2017

BACHELOR OF ARTS DEGREE

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

Previously graduated with Honors in Political Science.

Sept 2010 – Dec 2015 Exceptional standing with all professors.

CERTIFICATIONS

AMAZON WEB SERVICES
CERTIFICATE

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT - ASSOCIATE

 $Jan\ 2020-Jan\ 2023$

AMAZON WEB SERVICES
CERTIFICATE

CERTIFICATE CLOUD PRACTIONER

Dec 2019 – Dec 2022